204 Sweet Violet Dr • Holly Springs, NC 27540 253 888 9608 • christinaduwors@gmail.com

#### **PROFESSIONAL OBJECTIVE**

To provide value to an organization of like-minded professionals by applying my diverse work background to positively impact my colleagues and those I serve.

#### **PROFESSIONAL PROFILE**

I want to continue to develop and build on my diverse professional background with great energy, capability and empathy. I will bring a solid work ethic, excellent creativity, and outstanding collaboration skills. As a military spouse, I have learned to adapt and be a lifelong learner who will humbly and quickly integrate with the team. I work tirelessly to create a positive and enduring impact on the development and growth of those I serve. Please feel free to contact my references below regarding my experience.

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

Masters in Teaching, Social Science 5-12

WESTERN GOVERNORS UNIVERSITY, Salt Lake City, UT • May 2014

## State Licensures and Endorsement:

- Washington State Social Studies 5-12
- North Carolina Social Studies 9-12, Middle School Social Studies, Middle School Math

#### **Bachelors of Arts, History**

UNIVERSITY OF WASHINGTON, Seattle, WA • Jun 1994

• Study Abroad, Kobe, Japan

## **EXPERIENCE**

Math Teacher, Wake County Public Schools

Nov 2020 - Present

- Collaborated on three-person 6<sup>th</sup> grade math team
- Delivered and coordinated virtual and face to face instruction modalities
- Demonstrated flexibility and adaptability through variable education requirements due to COVID

#### Substitute Teacher, Wake County Public Schools

Sept 2019 – Oct 2020

Long-Term Substitute at Apex Middle School, Jan - Feb 2020 and Aug 2020 – Oct 2020

204 Sweet Violet Dr • Holly Springs, NC 27540 253 888 9608 • christinaduwors@gmail.com

Washington Career Pathways (WACAPA) Project Manager, Pierce College, Lakewood, WA Nov 2014 -Dec 2019

Supervisor: Jo Ann Baria, VP - Workforce, Economic & Professional Development, Pierce College Phone: 253-964-6640, 9401 Farwest Dr. SW, Lakewood, WA 98498

- Designed, developed and innovated the <a href="http://wacareerpaths.com/">http://wacareerpaths.com/</a> web site that collected educational and career resources in Washington state and streamlined users access to the specific resources most applicable for their situation
- Cultivated resource awareness and interaction through ongoing social media marketing campaigns notably increased web site interaction by 41% from Oct 2017 to Oct 2018 with 80% new viewers each week
- Managed the WACAPA Web Tool, <a href="http://washingtoncareerpathways.org/">http://washingtoncareerpathways.org/</a> and liasoned with the 34 Community and Technical Colleges in Washington state to provide resource access and training
- Developed more than 100 interactive Career Pathway Roadmaps for K12 and post-secondary institutions delineating wage and skill progression in over 30 career paths for advisement and guidance for maximizing employment outcomes
- Collaborated with K12 and Community College educational and community organizations to facilitate constituent career planning across Washington State: including Workforce Education Council of the State Board of Community and Technical Colleges, <u>Washington ACTE</u>, <u>Workforce Central</u> Tacoma, Washington State Department of Veterans Affairs, and Courage360 WA
- Coordinated with the Veteran's Affairs office and Hawke Transition Center to develop Veteran's Industry Education (VIE-25) and Apprentice Military Pathways information tools for transitioning service members at JBLM in Washington State
- Presented Career Exploration resources and information to local K12 classrooms, K12 Career and Technical Directors, High School and College school administrations, and employee organizations including Amazon.com in Tacoma
- Presented the Washington Career Pathways Project in collaboration with The Seattle Colleges
   District at the League for Innovation in the Community College in 2017
- Supervised Washington Career Pathway team including a Web designer, Hawke Transition Center VIE-25 Coordinator, and Pathways Assistant
- Planned, Applied and Executed yearly Perkins Special Project Grant Application encompassing the \$80,000 budget for WACAPA Project

Student Teacher, Vilseck American High School, Vilseck, Germany

Jan – Apr 2014

Supervisor: Tim Connelly, Phone: 011-49-9662-8505

 Designed, taught, and evaluated instructional units for 9<sup>th</sup> grade World History (Academic and Honors) and Sociology elective

204 Sweet Violet Dr • Holly Springs, NC 27540 253 888 9608 • christinaduwors@gmail.com

## Education Counselor, Army Soldier Education Center, Vilseck, Germany

Aug 2012- Jan 2014

Supervisor: Susan Sine, Education Services Officer, Phone: 011-49-9662-3394

- Developed working knowledge of GI Bill and Tuition Assistance programs
- Presented 40+ person In-processing/Out-processing briefings on Education, GI Bill, Career Planning
- Counseled Soldiers in implementing personal education and career planning, including degree selection and completion
- Ensured service member and family's understanding of Tuition Assistance Program and GI Bill Education Benefits
- Staffed Education Center information booth at community events
- Managed service member enrollment and progress data information in the Army Continuing Education Services (ACES) database

## Substitute Teacher, Vilseck American High School, Vilseck, Germany

Jan 2012- Dec 2013

Supervisor: Mr. Duane Werner, VHS Principal, Phone: 011-49-9662-8505

- Long-term substitute for fourth quarter
- Responsible for curriculum design and instruction for English Language Learner classes

## Office Manager, Dock Street Brokers, Inc., Seattle, WA

1994-1996 and 2001-2003

Supervisor: Roger Lohrer, Owner, Phone: 206-789-5101

- Managed office of fishing vessel and permit brokerage with more than 500 average listings
- Supervised part-time office assistant
- Managed office bank accounts, including trust accounts with balances up to \$1,000,000 dollars
- Compiled periodic financial reports for company President
- Designed, compiled and published annual 80 page international catalog of company listings
- Secured advertising sales of \$5,000 to pay for production costs
- Collaborated with industry partners to design ads for catalog and maintained company web site listings
- Facilitated broker interaction with industry government regulatory offices and clients
- •Designed and developed online inventory database in Filemaker Pro for broker use to streamline client/broker sales process

### **TECHNOLOGICAL SKILLS**

Apple and PC literate
Microsoft Office Suite
SmartBoard Technology
Social Media Marketing Platforms:

Instagram, Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn

Webtool and Website Design

Canva

Google Classroom Zoom Meeting Wordpress

204 Sweet Violet Dr • Holly Springs, NC 27540 253 888 9608 • <a href="mailto:christinaduwors@gmail.com">christinaduwors@gmail.com</a>

#### **REFERENCES**

Jo Ann Baria
Pierce College Vice President of Workforce, Economic & Professional Development
Lakewood, WA
253-964-6640
jbaria@pierce.ctc.edu

Mark Haskins Executive Director of Pierce College at JBLM 253-964-6606 mhaskins@pierce.ctc.edu

Maj. Rachel Roberts WA Department of Veterans Affairs Plans Officer Temporarily on duty in Wiesbaden Germany Cell: +49 0175 149 6135

Cell: +49 01/5 149 6135 WhatsApp: 571-721-0506